Luke Smith

Austin, TX 78751

Phone: (510) 517-3417 | Email: <u>lucasjfsmith@gmail.com</u>

Website: <u>lucasjfsmith.github.io/personal-website/</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/lukesmith5120

SUMMARY

Data and information systems professional with proven success in client-facing IT project and data management. Outstanding track record of leading cross-functional teams to implement software and achieve data-oriented solutions with extensive experience in complex data environments. Passionate analytical problem-solver with strong programming skills including SQL, Python, Java, and JavaScript. Dedicated to continued technical growth as demonstrated by certifications in data analytics and visualization and specialization in supervised and unsupervised machine learning. Driven to find an opportunity that combines unique technical and interpersonal skillset to solve challenging problems, work with passionate team members, and continue career growth.

SKILLS

General: Project Management, Client Management, Presentation, Hypothesis Testing Languages: Python, SQL, R, JavaScript, Java, JSON, HTML/CSS, C#, VBA, Regex, XML

Tools & Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Scikit Learn, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Excel, Spark, TensorFlow, Keras,

Spark, SQLAlchemy, Web Scraping, Flask API, NLP, NoSQL

Applications: Salesforce, GitHub, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Tableau, Looker, SFTP, Microsoft Office, Jira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Implementation Manager Iodine Software

October 2020 – March 2023 Austin, TX

- Led over 30 technical projects working with hospital IT departments to implements lodine's suite of machine learning products over a 6 14 week timeline
- Responsible for integration of millions of client data points including labs and vitals, medication, and provider documentation via the creation of a secure VPN, HL7 interfaces, and sFTP sites
- Performed in-depth data analysis, validation, and mapping efforts across client data, creating advanced SQL queries to ensure complete and successful data integration
- Enhanced medical documentation ML models by interpreting NLP engine outputs and identifying missed concepts with SQL queries utilizing regex
- Determined drivers of confidence outputs for medical evidence ML models by identifying model feature weights and cross-referencing case feature inputs
- Built and supported client-facing dashboards in Looker through understanding of underlying SQL scripts
- Embedded and tested client single sign-on technology, such as SAML and LDAP, within application
- Mentored new Implementation Managers during and beyond onboard shadowing process
- Served as Level Two escalation resource for Client Success Analysts working directly with end users

Client Success Analyst lodine Software

July 2019 – October 2020 Austin, TX

 Triaged and solved 20 to 50 technical issues reported by users per week through an in-depth understanding of lodine application, code base, data structure, and lifecycle

- Participated in data science model investigations to review machine learning outputs for over 50 models.
- Implemented machine learning model improvements by redesigning model escalation process to emphasize understanding, investigating, and translating client concerns to Data Science leadership
- Analyzed and summarized medical and application data using SQL and Excel data in conjunction with Account Managers to resolve client concerns, issues, and questions
- Tracked hundreds of Jira tickets to stay informed on prioritized and completed enhancement and bug tickets
- Created and contributed to Confluence articles to ensure up-to-date knowledge across organization
- Built and tested 30 custom indicators based on medical events using Java

PROJECTS

Personal Website | lucasifsmith.github.io/personal-website

 Static website built with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap featuring downloadable resume and links to personal projects seen below

Produce Cost Analysis | github.com/lucasjfsmith/agro-expo

• Jupyter notebook using pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Scipy to explore and analyze 20 years of produce farm prices as well as retail prices from Atlanta, Chicago, Los Angeles, and New York City.

Pro Venue Tracker | pro-venue-tracker.onrender.com | github.com/lucasjfsmith/pro-venue-tracker

- Cloud-based Flask app utilizing PostgreSQL, SQL Alchemy, Pandas, Leaflet.js interactive map to displays each professional sports team, venue, and next event across the MLB, NFL, NBA, NHL, and MLS
- Allows users to dynamically display leagues of their choosing and view venue and event information by clicking icons displayed on the coordinates of each venue
- Venue coordinates gathered from Kaggle.com, schedule information web-scraped from sports-reference.com, and additional information pulled from Geoapify API

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Program Director Lair of the Bear

March 2018 – August 2018 Pinecrest, CA

- Managed a staff of 30, coordinating food, maintenance, entertainment, and recreation operations in remote wilderness environment
- Responsible for customer satisfaction, fielding and prioritizing issues and resources, determining possible solutions, and relaying all resolutions directly to customers

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

Explore AustinSub-Mentor

2022 – Present
Austin, TX

Available as a substitute mentor for outdoor activities with Austin youth

BORP Adaptive Sports Revolution Fundraiser

2020 – Present Berkeley, CA

Annual bike ride fundraiser raising money for people with disabilities in the Bay Area

EDUCATION

Coursera

Machine Learning Specialization

July 2023 - Present

- Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification; Advance Learning Algorithms; Unsupervised Learning, Recommenders, Reinforcement Learning taught by Professor Andrew Ng of Stanford University
- Courses emphasize understanding of math and concepts underlying common algorithms like regression, clustering, decision trees, and neural networks

University of Texas at Austin Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

March 2023 - August 2023

 Six month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Spark, and Machine Learning.

University of Texas at Austin
BBA in Management Information Systems

2015 - 2019